<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Srikar Gudipati</title>
 <link href="http://srikarg.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://srikarg.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-04-14T00:18:09-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://srikarg.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Srikar Gudipati</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Governor's First Update</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/governor's-blog/governors-first-update"/>
   <updated>2015-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/governor's-blog/governors-first-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello New Jersey Key Clubbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Josie Suddeth and I am extremely honored and excited to serve as your District Governor for the 2015-2016 Service Year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As promised in my campaign, I will be posting a monthly blog on the New Jersey District Website. I hope to further bridge the gap between club and district, and let you know what the district is up to through this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I will be your District Governor this year, I want to give you a little brief overview of who I am. The way to success is when the leader works as his or her followers. I want to be as relatable and approachable as possible. If you want to learn even more about me and my goals for this year, go to the board tab on the website, click on me, and read my Letter of Introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name: Josie Suddeth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past Key Club Positions: Lieutenant Governor of Division 7, Vice President, Historian&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Colors: Light blue, pink, lime green, and lavender&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theme Song: Walking on Sunshine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Book: The Hunger Games Series by Suzanne Collins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Movie: The Parent Trap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Song: I Lived by One Republic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Food: Apple Crisp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Quote: “It doesn’t matter where you go, but what you do when you are there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Key Club Service Project: My club held a joint project with Pennsylvania K-Family members my freshman year to help with Hurricane Sandy Relief. We had a 2 mile beach clean-up, gave cupcakes to emergency responders, and ran a lunch for those still displaced by the storm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funniest Key Club Moment: At Midwinter 2014, my room’s alarm clock didn’t go off and we had to rush to get to the session on time. I whipped out running while on the way to the elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Favorite Key Club Event: I can’t pick just one! They are all so fun, informative and unique in their own respective ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing seeing a lot of you at DCON 2015! I hope you enjoyed the experience as much as I did. DCON 2016 will be even more exciting; I hope to see all underclassmen there next year!
The most important thing the District Board is working on right now is Regional Training Conferences.  Regional Training Conferences are events run by our district where attendees have the opportunity to attend a general session, attend fascinating workshops, eat 2 great meals, and get the chance to win Key Club prizes! These workshops range from specific officer positions to Fundraising Ideas, to How to Get More Involved in Your Division! They are especially helpful for new officers to learn more about their jobs, but general members get just as much if not more out of the experience. Regional Training Conferences are quickly approaching! While the exact locations are not yet solidified, one will definitely be held in southern New Jersey and the other in northern New Jersey. The dates for the two Spring RTCs are May 9th and May 16th and they will both be from 9am-1pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another exciting event happening in the Key Club world is International Convention. This year International Convention is in Indianapolis, Indiana (the best city in the country to hold a convention). International Convention is kind of like DCON but 100 times better and bigger. Attendees attend general sessions, attend caucus sessions, elect the International Board, attend workshops, explore the host city, mingle with Key Clubbers from all over the world, and so much more. On top of the educational part of ICON, attendees will attend a block party, attend a minor league baseball game, attend the largest pancake breakfast ever, and attend a private Hello, Goodbye concert and more! This year is particularly exciting because it is the 100th anniversary of Kiwanis International. Kiwanis, Circle K, and Key Club are holding one joint International Convention. ICON is the must go to event of the Key Club year! For New Jersey Key Clubbers, ICON will begin on June 23rd and end June 30th. On top of the exciting ICON schedule, our district will travel to Hershey Park in Hershey, Pennsylvania; Columbus, Ohio; The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in Cleveland, Ohio; and Cedar Point Amusement Park in Sandusky, Ohio! I will be attending and I hope to see you there as well. The first payment is due by May 8th to District Administrator Ms. McCann. If you would like the registration packet, please contact your Lieutenant Governor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some exciting things I specifically have and will be doing are the following. I have been busily and happily working with all aspects of the District to make sure we start off on the right foot! These range from talking to board members, planning committee work, and planning RTCs! I will be attending the Governor’s and Administrator’s Training Conference in Atlanta, Georgia in about 2 weeks where I will learn how to better serve you. The District Board has its first official board meeting this weekend. Be on the lookout for updates from this meeting!
Thank you for reading this blog post and I look forward to seeing you at upcoming district events!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours in Caring and Service,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josie Suddeth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015-2016 New Jersey District Governor&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>District Eliminathon 2015</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/district-eliminathon"/>
   <updated>2015-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/district-eliminathon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&#39;position: relative; padding-bottom: 51%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&#39;iframe&#39; src=&#39;http://flickrit.com/slideshowholder.php?height=50&amp;size=big&amp;count=100&amp;setId=72157650739078545&amp;counter=true&amp;thumbnails=1&amp;transition=0&amp;layoutType=responsive&amp;sort=0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;style=&#39;width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;&#39; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Key Leader 2014</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/key-leader"/>
   <updated>2015-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/key-leader</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&#39;position: relative; padding-bottom: 51%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&#39;iframe&#39; src=&#39;http://flickrit.com/slideshowholder.php?height=50&amp;size=big&amp;count=100&amp;setId=72157649924768709&amp;counter=true&amp;thumbnails=1&amp;transition=0&amp;layoutType=responsive&amp;sort=0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;style=&#39;width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;&#39; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scholarship Information</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/scholarship-information"/>
   <updated>2014-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/scholarship-information</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Salutations, New Jersey District Key Clubbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it may seem like the service year just began, it is quickly coming to a close!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of you, this year will be the last for your Key Club career. Fortunately, you have the opportunity to be rewarded for your dedication to Key Club! Each year, the New Jersey District grants 14 different scholarships, each ranging between $1,000-$2,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All information is located in the scholarship packet. You can ask your Lieutenant Governor for a packet, but here is a quick breakdown of what you need to include in your application:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A two page essay detailing your favorite Key Club service project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two letters of recommendation from adults who are familiar with your service, neither of which can be a relative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advisor verification of your service, especially if you must approximate your number of hours/points, in the case that your club does not record hours/points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief description of all your service, inside and outside of Key Club, and your greatest achievement outside of Key Club.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All scholarship applications must be postmarked by February 20th, 2015. Any application not postmarked by this date will not be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scholarship recipients will be announced at District Convention!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to reading about your favorite service projects! If you have any questions, please feel free to contact &lt;a href=&quot;/board/farwa.html&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours in Caring and Service,
Farwa Shakeel&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fall Rally 2014</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/fall-rally"/>
   <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/fall-rally</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&#39;position: relative; padding-bottom: 51%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&#39;iframe&#39; src=&#39;http://flickrit.com/slideshowholder.php?height=50&amp;size=big&amp;count=100&amp;setId=72157648357627030&amp;counter=true&amp;thumbnails=1&amp;transition=0&amp;layoutType=responsive&amp;sort=0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;style=&#39;width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;&#39; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>North Fall RTC at Parsippany Hills High School</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/north-fall-rtc"/>
   <updated>2014-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/photos/north-fall-rtc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&#39;position: relative; padding-bottom: 51%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&#39;iframe&#39; src=&#39;http://flickrit.com/slideshowholder.php?height=50&amp;size=big&amp;count=100&amp;setId=72157647471634169&amp;counter=true&amp;thumbnails=1&amp;transition=0&amp;layoutType=responsive&amp;sort=0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;style=&#39;width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;&#39; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What to Expect at Fall Rally</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/what-to-expect-at-fall-rally"/>
   <updated>2014-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/what-to-expect-at-fall-rally</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to Get Animated with Service at Fall Rally 2014? What is Fall Rally? Fall Rally is the largest gathering of NJ Key Clubbers to motivate Key Clubbers to have a great rest of the service year. This year Fall Rally will be on October 12th at Six Flags Great Adventure in Jackson, New Jersey. In the wee hours of the morning you and your Key Club will travel to the amusement park to meet about 3,000 Key Clubbers from all across New Jersey! Get ready to see the NJ District Board dress up as your favorite animated characters ranging from Aang to Wanda! Get ready to learn all about what the New Jersey District is doing ranging from Eliminate updates, Advocacy information, dues, and different district events during the session!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another highlight of the event will be the spirit stick competition! Every division will have to prove how ready they are for the service year as they cheer their heads off hoping to be the loudest division in the district! The winner will win the coveted spirit stick! The day does not have to end with this fun session! Clubs have the option to explore the park and go on the rides before the park officially opens! Your club will also have the option to stay for Fright Fest.
Although Fall Rally is on October 12th, Key Clubs should start preparing now! You should be sure to stress the importance of attending Fall Rally from the start of the school year and then talk to your current Lieutenant Governor or any District Board member about how many people your club will be taking to Fall Rally or if there is an issue or concern regarding transportation, etc. Fall Rally is great way to get to know people who share the same passion for service as you, meet the members of the New Jersey District Board, and have lots of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Registration:&lt;/strong&gt; $37.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season Pass:&lt;/strong&gt; $6.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late Registration:&lt;/strong&gt; $41.00&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spring Regional Training Conferences Recap</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/spring-rtcs-recap"/>
   <updated>2014-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/spring-rtcs-recap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year’s Spring Regional Training Conferences were a success. The hard work of the host clubs and the New Jersey District Board members who helped choreograph the events paid off as Key Clubbers from all over New Jersey successfully learned the ins and outs of everything Key Club. The Spring Regional Training Conferences were held in Roxbury for the Northern session on May 4, 2014, and in Cedar Creek (co-hosted by the Cedar Creek and Absegami Key Clubs) for the Southern session on May 10, 2014. Both ran from 9 am to 1 pm, with every minute full of learning and laughter. The RTC theme this service year is Greek/Roman mythology, as the New Jersey District is trying to climb Mount Service! The host clubs did a spectacular job in decorating their school to fit the theme. Their hard work with decorations helped provide Key Clubbers the ultimate experience at the conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with theme-related decorations, Key Clubbers attended creative workshops, such as &lt;em&gt;Bringing in the Drachmas: Fundraising and Speaking like Roman Emperor: Public Speaking&lt;/em&gt;. The workshops were all split up into three sessions, each one also named to correspond with the theme. The first session, Session Alpha, referred to the first letter of the Greek alphabet. Session Mu, the second session, was named after the twelfth and middle letter of the Greek alphabet. The last session, Session Omega, referred to the last letter of the Greek alphabet. A wide variety of workshops were given during each session, from workshops that taught club officers about their positions to ones that explained how general members can get involved to workshops that addressed the district projects for this service year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people attended the spring conferences, and each person had their own great and unique experience. Kenneth Ye, President of Egg Harbor Township Key Club in Division 2, said, “The Spring RTC’s were invigorating and eye-opening with the variety of workshops and events for officers and fellow Key Club members! It was truly amazing experience that allowed me to gain further knowledge and skills to help me with my position in Key Club, and it was great to meet everyone around our area.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After such a great spring session, the NJ District Board has high expectations for an even better fall session! The Fall Northern RTCs will be on September 20, 2014; Central RTCs will be on September 14, 2014; and Southern will be on September 13, 2014. While club officers are required to attend a Regional Training Conference in order to be distinguished, all Key Clubbers are encouraged to attend a Fall RTCeven if they already attended one in the spring! There will be exciting icebreakers, updated information, and new workshops like “You, Your Ltg., and Your Division” and “Get that Olympic Gold: Contests and DCON,” all of which promise a day of useful information and many smiles.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Public Relations Committee</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-public-relations-committee"/>
   <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-public-relations-committee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PR means telling the truth and working ethically - even when all the media want is headlines and all the public wants is scapegoats. Public relations fails when there is no integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Viv Segal&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/prY5tTG7Dns&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Public Relations Committee is dedicated to promoting the ideals of Key Club and its works through the creation and use of various sources of media to fit public needs. Through the usage of such forms of social media as Facebook and Twitter, as well as the distribution of flyers and creation of videos, we hope to present the New Jersey District of Key Club International in a fun, hands-on manner that both serves to relay relevant information as well as interact with each member on a social media based level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three subcommittees in Public Relations: Publicize, Inform, and Promotion, with the co-chairs, District Editor Patrick Quinn and Lieutenant Governor of Division 16 David Guirgis, taking active roles in all committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Publicize&lt;/em&gt; subcommittee, &lt;a href=&quot;/board/darren.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Darren Khong&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/srikar.html&quot;&gt;District Webmaster Srikar Gudipati&lt;/a&gt;, made presentations regarding the benefits of attending Regional Training Conferences and Fall Rally. The media, local newspapers within each RTC host town, was contacted, and various discussions were made about how to continue publicizing District events, with suggestions ranging from social media countdowns to Vines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Inform&lt;/em&gt; committee, &lt;a href=&quot;/board/jae.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Jae Shin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/harsh.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Harsh Patel&lt;/a&gt;, is working on creating informational brochures and presentations for recently chartered Key Clubs and target schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Promotion&lt;/em&gt; subcommittee, &lt;a href=&quot;/board/jae.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Jae Shin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/darren.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Darren Khong&lt;/a&gt;, is creating plans for promotional commercials and videos for New Jersey Key Club events specifically Fall Rally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each subcommittee seems separate from the other, excellent communication with the rest of the NJ District has allowed for greater integration and involvement within each other’s committees, as well as a greater sense of planning when deciding what needs to be done. After all, even with each subcommittee, we are still Public Relations: dedicated to serving, informing and entertaining all of you avid and dedicated Key Clubbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to hear more from us soon. We can’t wait to show you what we have planned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The International Programs Committee</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-international-programs-committee"/>
   <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-international-programs-committee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-brief-introduction-to-the-international-programs-committee&quot;&gt;A brief introduction to the International Programs Committee&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International Programs is the focus of Key Club on a global scale. It takes the core values and enthusiasm from Key Clubbers and extends it across the country. From teaching members at Key Leader and ICON to connecting with outside organizations such as UNICEF, the International Programs Committee seeks to spread the message of Key Club to other communities. It combines the service of members with the assistance and dedication of partner organizations to better assist the entire world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-various-subcommittees-of-the-international-programs-committee&quot;&gt;The various subcommittees of the International Programs Committee&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;icon&quot;&gt;ICON&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/board/thomas.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Thomas Michael&lt;/a&gt; has been working on the International Convention subcommittee for International Programs, and so far, he has created an ICON flyer for each Lieutenant Governor to send out to their clubs. With some help from &lt;a href=&quot;/board/nathaniel.hml&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Nate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/latifa.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Latifa&lt;/a&gt; he was able to establish a very nice flyer for our district mailing. He will be attending ICON and will be prepared to write a recap on our adventure in California. Additionally, Thomas is working on a trifold for the ICON service fair! ICON is very rapidly approaching and Thomas is very excited for the great experiences he will have there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unicef&quot;&gt;UNICEF&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Club International has three main service partners, one of which being UNICEF. It is the only organization from the United Nations that focuses on children nearly exclusively. UNICEF shares the Kiwanis family’s universal dedication to children and service by providing extensive resources and leadership to help eliminate Iodine Deficiency Disorder (IDD) permanently. Over the years, Key Club has been a primary advocate of UNICEF. Since 1994 Key Club has raised almost $5 million towards the elimination of Iodine Deficiency Disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Club and the other branches of the Kiwanis family are working with UNICEF for the Eliminate Project. The Eliminate Project is a global campaign to raise money to eliminate maternal and neonatal tetanus from the world. Tetanus is a deadly disease that comes from spores in the dirt. During unsafe birthing routines, these spores are able to enter the mother and baby’s bodies causing infection. The first few hours of the baby’s life is filled with excruciating pain and sensitivity to even a mother’s touch. Key Club’s goal is to raise $110 million by the end of the 2015 service year. The most popular way Key Clubbers work with UNICEF is in fall with Trick-or-Treat for UNICEF. During October, leading up to Halloween, Key Clubbers collect loose change from students throughout school days and they also ask for change instead of candy when they go Trick-or-Treat. Some even establish competition to see who can raise the most money! Trick-or-Treat for UNICEF can happen almost anytime you go out or see your friends, so always have your little box by your side!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trick-or-Treat for UNICEF although the most popular is not the only way to raise money for UNICEF. Clubs can implement their own ideas to raise funds for such a great cause!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;march-of-dimes&quot;&gt;March of Dimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March of Dimes is an organization that works to raise both money and awareness about thousands of premature births that happen every year. There are walks organized by March of Dimes set to raise funds and awareness. All that is required of members is to walk with both friends and strangers toward the common goal. March of Dimes has supported causes spanning from the fight against polio to defending babies and mothers. The program was established by FDR over fifty years ago, and continues to raise awareness and funds for its goals. The money they raise is used for research that helps to protect babies and mothers everywhere. This year our district intends to raise $8,100.  This represents that out of every 8 babies to be born, 1 will be premature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the March! Walks take place during the spring and there should be a one near you. If you can get at least 18% of your club to attend, you will win an award at District Convention! Bring as many people as you can- friends, family, peers- to stand together and take part in the March!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-children&amp;#39;s-miracle-network&quot;&gt;The Children&amp;#39;s Miracle Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Children&amp;#39;s Miracle Network is one of Key Club&amp;#39;s three preferred charities. CMN is an non-profit organization that works around the world to raise funds for children&amp;#39;s hospitals, medical research, and community awareness. They have given over $4 billion to over 170 hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Club works to help these hospitals by volunteering to spend time with patients and raise money through various fundraisers. Currently, the New Jersey District focuses on Children&amp;#39;s Specialized Hospital, that has locations in Toms River, Egg Harbor Township, Clifton, Fanwood, Hamilton, Mountainside, New Brunswick, and Roselle Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our service goal for Children&amp;#39;s Miracle Network Hospitals is 1,704 hours of volunteering. The 4 represents the $4 billion donated, and the 170 represents the 170 hospitals that are a part of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only will volunteering make the day of a patient, it will make yours as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relay-for-life&quot;&gt;Relay for Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May is Cancer Awareness Month. One major event during this time is Relay For Life, run by the American Cancer Society. This community event allows everyone to remember those who have passed, remember those have beat their battle, and to fundraise for the costs of medical care and research to end this terrible disease. Held in over 20 countries in over 5000 events, Relay For Life has more than 4 million people participate annually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can my Key Club help fight cancer through Relay for Life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clubs can make teams and raise money. Not only would you be fundraising, but it would also be a social event. Promote the ability to have fun, walk, and talk during the Relay. Key Clubbers can also serve on the committee to help plan the actual event. To publicize the event, clubs can also “paint the town purple” to spread awareness for cancer and get the word out about the local Relay for Life.  Southern Regional in Manahawkin runs the Survivors Dinner in which cancer survivors are fed and view centerpieces relating to the theme. They also paint their school purple by putting “I CAN” signs up and by changing the bulletin board paper to purple. This annual event not only creates plenty of hours, but it also makes the Key Clubber feel good about helping to fight such a terrible illness. For more information about Relay for Life or an event near you, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.relayforlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.relayforlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-leader&quot;&gt;Key Leader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Leader is a Kiwanis-run educational program that provides life-changing experiences to teach students about how to become better leaders through various workshops, team building exercises, a ropes course, and so much more. Another important part of this event is that all attendees are broken into teams, or “neighborhoods,” made up of students from around the area. This allows you to meet new people and forge new connections while simultaneously building your skills as a leader. This event is open to all high school students and 8th graders looking to become better servant leaders. Key Leader will be held from December 5th-7th at Cross Roads Camp in Port Murray, New Jersey. The cost for this weekend is $200 and includes great food, rooming, and obviously fun. Key Clubbers receive a discount, and if you have been to the event before, you can apply to be a student facilitator to receive an additional discount. Registration is completed online. For more information about Key Leader, ask your Lieutenant Governor or visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.key-leader.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.key-leader.org/&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yof&quot;&gt;YOF&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Youth Opportunity Organizations or Outside Organizations is a subcommittee regarding the International Programs committee. As members of this subcommittee, our main goals are to spread the word about other outside organizations that we do not specifically endorse as a District and to promote the Youth Opportunities Fund. This fund allows members serve the world by providing grants for service opportunities that may need more funding. We are also responsible for speaking about an outside organization at Fall Rally in order to spread the word to over 3,000 Key Clubbers about another worthy charity. We  spread the word of our subcommittee through articles like this when asked by District Webmaster Srikar or District Editor Patrick and create flyers to be distributed to the district. Regarding our service to lieutenant governors, we create flyers and articles to be distributed in their newsletters so that their divisions can learn about the world of different charities regularly. In summation, we work together to serve the New Jersey District and spread the word that there is a world of charities and people that need our help beyond the charities specifically endorsed by the New Jersey District. We are spreading the love of service on a broader scale. If you have any questions regarding the Youth Opportunities Fund or if your club is looking for an upcoming, worthy charity to help, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;/board/josie.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Josie Suddeth&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The District Project Steering Committee</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-district-project-steering-committee"/>
   <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-district-project-steering-committee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Salutations, Key Clubbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-this-year&amp;#39;s-district-project?&quot;&gt;What is this year&amp;#39;s District Project?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the New Jersey District has once again chosen the ELIMINATE Project as the District Project! The ELIMINATE Project is a global effort to eradicate maternal and neonatal tetanus, a life-threatening disease that takes the life of one baby every 9 minutes, from this world. A baby that is infected with tetanus only lives between 3 and 7 days, dying after suffering excruciating pain and sensitivity to light and touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-the-kiwanis-family-doing-to-help?&quot;&gt;What is The Kiwanis Family doing to help?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Kiwanis International teamed up with the ELIMINATE Project to help in the effort to rid the world of tetanus. With 25 countries remaining still afflicted with the disease, and one more year left in the ELIMINATE Project campaign, Kiwanis and Key Club International are making their best efforts to help the Project reach its goal. Each year, the District Project Steering (DPS) Committee decides on a fundraising goal for the District!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-this-year&amp;#39;s-fundraising-goal?&quot;&gt;What is this year&amp;#39;s fundraising goal?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the Committee has set a fundraising goal of: $109,325.15, representing the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10: For 2010, the year Kiwanis and the ELIMINATE Project joined forces to eradicate tetanus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9: For the one baby that dies of tetanus every 9 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3: For the series of 3 vaccinations needed to immunize a mother and her future babies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25: For the 25 countries that remain affected by MNT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15: For 2015, the year the ELIMINATE Project campaign ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DPS Committee is responsible for monitoring and encouraging fundraising all over the district, keeping track of progress being made on the fundraising goal. ELIMINATE Week is also the responsibility of DPS. The committee comes up with an activity for each day of the week, whether it be showing off the ELIMINATE spirit or raising funds for the project. All clubs are encouraged to participate in ELIMINATE Week and host as many fundraisers as possible this service year, not only to help reach the District fundraising goal but also to benefit the ELIMINATE Project to the fullest in the last year of its campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck and happy fundraising, New Jersey District!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The District Programs Committee</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-district-programs-committee"/>
   <updated>2014-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/committee-reports/the-district-programs-committee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-the-district-programs-committee?&quot;&gt;What is the District Programs Committee?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The District Programs Committee focuses on advocacy and the entire K-Family relationship. The committee chooses the advocacy focus for the service year for the entire New Jersey District of Key Club International. It also works to organize and strengthen relations between the different K-Family Branches in the New Jersey District. District Programs is comprised of three subcommittees: Advocacy, K-Family Growth, and K-Family Relations. Co-chairs of this committee are &lt;a href=&quot;/board/tara.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Tara Engelken of Division 9&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/brooke.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Brooke Willemstyn of Division 10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-the-advocacy-subcommittee-do?&quot;&gt;What does the Advocacy Subcommittee do?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Advocacy Subcommittee is focused on raising awareness about the district advocacy project which is hunger in the United States. It aims towards conducting service projects rather than fundraising. Through hands-on projects and advocacy, the campaign strives to make a difference in the district on the topic of hunger. &lt;a href=&quot;/board/dianna.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Dianna&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/board/devin.html&quot;&gt;Lieutenant Governor Devin&lt;/a&gt; of Divisions 2 and 12 respectively serve as co-chairs to this subcommittee. They have helped shape the focus for the 2014-2015 service year, and are looking into the ways to expand upon it. Alongside working with Students Change Hunger, a competition created by the Federation of New Jersey Food Banks to challenge students to raise food for the less fortunate, Dianna and Devin are looking into several other creative options to raise awareness for domestic hunger, and are sure to make great strides this service year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-the-k-family-growth-subcommittee-do?&quot;&gt;What does the K-Family Growth Subcommittee do?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K-Family Growth strives to create new K-Family clubs. Whether it’s a Key Club, K-Kids Club, Builders Club, or another branch, the purpose is to increase the number of service clubs throughout the district. The goal is to create 1 Kiwanis, 1 Key Club, 1 K-Kids, and 1 Builders Club by District Convention 2015. &lt;a href=&quot;/board/alex.html&quot;&gt;Alex Marino&lt;/a&gt;, Lieutenant Governor of Division 1, has begun to seek out target clubs to further expand the New Jersey District. He hopes to exceed the required goal of created clubs, and we believe he will undoubtedly succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-does-the-k-family-relations-subcommittee-do?&quot;&gt;What does the K-Family Relations Subcommittee do?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K-Family Relations’ goal is to strengthen the relationship between the K-Family clubs in the New Jersey District. They promote events with other branches of the K-Family and keep the circle of K-Family information flowing through out the district. Chair &lt;a href=&quot;/board/bobbie.html&quot;&gt;Bobbie Boettinger&lt;/a&gt;, Lieutenant Governor of Division 19 has worked feverishly in assembling directories, contacting Circle K, and working on events hoped to be held later on in this service year. She hopes to expand these connections so the New Jersey District can see projects incorporating every branch of the K Family.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LTG Division 10 Says Hello!</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/ltg-division-10-says-hello"/>
   <updated>2014-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/ltg-division-10-says-hello</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! My name is Brooke Willemstyn, the appointed lieutenant governor of division 10 of the great NJ District. This year, I&amp;#39;ll try to stress communication from the district level to the club level, and keep all my presidents as informed as they can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;attention-club-officers-of-division-10!&quot;&gt;Attention Club Officers of Division 10!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have officially called you out for this service year. Make your general members feel important. They are the essence of Key Club! I am responsible to flow information from the district level, to the club officer level, but I need to be certain you don&amp;#39;t stop the flow there. Other members need to know what&amp;#39;s going on in order to want to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;attention-club-officers-of-the-nj-district&quot;&gt;Attention Club Officers of the NJ District&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of you are lucky in sliding by with a lazy lieutenant governor. The board this year is absolutely fabulous, and they will be on top of everything you do, so don&amp;#39;t let them down!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-i-expect-(division-10-specific)&quot;&gt;What I Expect (Division 10 Specific)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect you forward my newsletters, flyers, and all informational or promotional files to your clubs. I require that everyone fills out the forms I send early, and at worst on time. If that means the secretary is on vacation in Guatemala for a month, either your club CMRF is in before she leaves, or another officer is filling out the club monthly report form for that month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-you-should-expect&quot;&gt;What You Should Expect&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should expect change. You should be seeing some of the ideas your club has envisioned being realized on the district level. Expect me to communicate with you, and for Division 10 to have the best divisional projects in the district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this post, be professional, responsible, and lead this division 10 and our NJ District towards success this service year!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Governor's Welcome</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/governor's-welcome"/>
   <updated>2014-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/governor's-welcome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello New Jersey District,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main goals for this year are to have better district events, improve communication, and build K Families. Each of my goals is extremely important and it is club members such as ourselves that make Key Club possible. I hope to hear from you soon with any comments questions or concerns you may have. My email is &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:njgovernorlevisay@gmail.com&quot;&gt;NJGovernorLevisay@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; and I would be more than happy to just chat about Key Club or send you my newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this new year upon us the New Jersey District Board has been working fervently to keep the District up to date. From ELIMINATE week to RTCs we have been very busy making sure you are informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this date I have personally accomplished the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtained Governor files from the Immediate-Past Governor Ryan Clarkin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kept in contact with district board members in order to ensure all committees and clubs are in good contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kept in very close contact with District Adminstrator Ms.McCann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent out my Letter of Introduction to the New Jersey District Board of Trustees, Kiwanis Committee of Key Club, International President, and anyone who requested it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed committee preference sheets and formed both the standing committees and special event committees for the 2014/2015 service year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modified all committee directives and emailed them to the appropriate recipients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent out committee final reports to all chairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modified all Officersí Training Manuals to be handed out to Lieutenant Governors at the April board meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed up for the Governors-Administrators Training  Conference held in Indianapolis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created the agendas and prepared for the April Executive and District Board Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kept in contact with the District Board, Kiwanis Committee, International Council and various Key Clubbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitted my Governor Monthly Report for March/April&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended the SLP reporting call for New Jersey to talk about New Jersey&amp;#39;s progress with the ELIMINATE Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent out the current dues report and informed LTGs of non dues paid clubs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registered for ICON 2014!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacted every LTG and Executive member atleast once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The District's New Website</title>
   <link href="http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/the-districts-new-website"/>
   <updated>2014-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://srikarg.github.com/news/blog/announcements/the-districts-new-website</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-new-website&quot;&gt;The New Website&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! This is your District Webmaster Srikar, and I am proud to announce that the new district website has been released!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what&amp;#39;s-different?&quot;&gt;What&amp;#39;s Different?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of design, not much has changed since the last version of the website. I greatly appreciate the design skills of our former webmaster, Yuya Jeremy Ong. However, I have added several new features to the website that make it even easier to access and gain information from! The following is a list of those changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website is now mobile-friendly. What does this mean you ask? Well, now you can browse the district website on small screens without having to scroll around and zoom in and out. In short, the contents of the website fit to any screen that you may have. Try resizing your browser now!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each district board member now has their own blog! You can see the posts of a member by clicking on their name in the &lt;a href=&quot;/board/&quot;&gt;board section of our website&lt;/a&gt;! For example, click &lt;a href=&quot;/board/srikar.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see my posts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also find the contact information and introduction letter of a member on the same page as the blog posts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a new calendar page on the website which has a Google Calendar. This calendar will be updated with various district events, so it&amp;#39;s a good idea to sync it with your phone and computer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now find Key Clubs near your location by visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/district-map&quot;&gt;District Map Page&lt;/a&gt;! Once the page loads, allow it to access your location and soon, you will see a map with markers indicating Key Clubs near your current area. Try zooming in and out of the map to find more Key Clubs!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added a new &lt;a href=&quot;/quotes&quot;&gt;Quotes Page&lt;/a&gt; which includes several inspirational quotes that the District Board and Key Clubbers have found! Have a new quote? Send it to my email (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:njwebmastersrikar@gmail.com&quot;&gt;njwebmastersrikar@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;) with the subject line &lt;em&gt;New Quote For District Website&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Clubbers can comment on blog posts now! Please note that comments are approved by the District Board before they are posted. This system is in place to prevent spam comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;help-me-out!&quot;&gt;Help Me Out!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am only human and therefore make mistakes! If you find any errors or have suggestions for &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt; at all, please email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:njwebmastersrikar@gmail.com&quot;&gt;njwebmastersrikar@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
